## **David Duran**

San Francisco CA, 94103

Phone: (520) 285-6876 | Email: <u>David.Duran.3@Hotmail.com</u> | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-duran-b99a3894/

### **SUMMARY**

Data Science professional and Hospitality Expert with proven technical and leadership aptitude in data analysis and operations management. Business oriented, with qualifications that encompass partnering with business, leadership, and teams to define needs with creatively unique points of view, presenting and evaluating risks and issues. Adaptable, responsible and capacitated to implement architecture, tools, and best practices to enhance decision-making, cost control, and drive competitive business growth.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, VBA

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, GIT, Flask, Command-Line, Tableau

Tools: Excel, Pandas, NumPy, Visual Studio Code

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Warehouse Operations Manager SnackpassLLC (Not Just Snacks)

Nov2021-Aug2022 Hayward, CA

- Managed a 5-person Operation of hardware techs, developed automations to successfully carry out warehouse orders of hardware across the US.
- Developed production line efficiency and successfully communicated with the company necessary information to enhance product satisfaction, declaring baseline operations
- Partnered with product engineers and developed user interaction improvement of different products.
- Developed data mining tools to increase overall warehouse efficiency and report our results to influence company expansion strategies through google sheets.
- Communicated project updates and feedback across diverse stakeholders to ensure project successes during first stages of warehouse settlement.
- Organized and executed training events to third-party field techs that aligned with the values of the company and customer satisfaction strategies.

# Freelance Business Analyst Medical Operations

Jul2020-Sep2021

Bay Area, CA

- Prioritized requirements and collaborated with business owners to deliver overall better service and operations presentation,
- Developed efficiency tools to control training costs, enhance workflow and increase profit by up to 30%.
- Built tools and automations to increase medical insurance claim proficiency, and increased revenue.
- Designed standards, and training guidelines to increase patient satisfaction with proven revenue increase
- Analyzed surrounding market to specify patient market and increase business demands.

# Performance Development Manager Marriott International

2012 - 2020

Bay Area, CA

Developed department specific training, excel reports and tools to increase overall performance and

- efficiency in low performance hotel departments in a market of 3000+ employees.
- Collaborated directly with executive teams to strategize hotel-wide training and development efficiency.
- Partnered with properties across the Bay Area market to present trends, opportunities and victories specific to a hotel property through the analysis of business data.
- Delivered and managed new System Integrations, tracking training, success and efficiency through different softwares and tools.
- Onboarded 100+ new employees and maintained records of their personal growth and mentorship.

### **EDUCATION**

### Berkeley University—Certificate in Data Analytics, Berkeley CA

2023

• Six month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

## Northern Arizona University— Hospitality and Restaurant Management, Flagstaff AZ

2017

• Six month intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**Languages:** Native fluency in Spanish, English, professional proficiency in French and ASL **Adult Experiential Learning Facilitator:** Experience developing teams through experiential learning courses aiming to enhance team productivity, performance development and efficiency